In the second trimester, women..
في الثلث الثاني من الحمل ، عند النساء ..
Are probably focusing a little bit more on..
ربما تُركِزن أكثر قليلاً على ..
the fact that they actually having a baby
حقيقة إنجابهم لطفل بالفعل
to thinking about things like you know what rooms the baby going to go into.
للتفكير في أشياء مثل, تحديد اي غرفة ستكون للطفل.
What kind of mum am i going to be
أي نوع من الأمهات سأكون
they've started to perhaps do antenatal classes
ربما بدأن في حضور دروس ما قبل الولادة
so they getting a little bit more information.
حتى يحصلن على مزيد من المعلومات.
They're getting to know their health provider hopefully,
و من المفترض أن يتعرفوا على مقدم الرعاية الصحية الخاص بهم.
and getting more and more informed
وأن يحصلوا على المزيد والمزيد من المعلومات
and they started to have conversations with mothers and sisters and
وبدأوا في إجراء محادثات مع الأمهات والأخوات و..
and other friends about birth which they may not have had those conversations in the
وغيرهم من الأصدقاء حول الولادة الذين ربما لم
first twelve weeks.
يجروا تلك المحادثات في الأسابيع الاثني عشر الأولى.
Cause some women want to kind of keep the pregnancy quiet.
لأن بعض النساء يرغبن في الحفاظ على الحمل هادئًا.
The nausea generally eases off.
يخف الغثيان بشكل عام.
The sense of tiredness can ease women often feel much better
يمكن للشعور بالتعب أن يخف
and they feel much more pregnant.
ويشعرن بأنهن اصبحن حامل بالفعل.
Women said to start to feel quite glowing and.
و يبدأ النساء بالإحساس بأنهم افضل حالاً
Generally it's probably the most healthy
بشكل عام ، إنها افضل فترة لصحتهن
And wellest.
و سلامتهن
Period during pregnancy.
أثناء فترة الحمل.
The hormones are settling
الهرمونات تستقر
more in the second trimester and it was
أكثر في الفصل الثاني, وكان كذلك..
it's like it's the time that you actually start enjoying the pregnancy.
إنه الوقت الذي تبدأ فيه بالفعل بالاستمتاع بالحمل.
you stop feeling the baby move for the first time, and..
توقفت عن الشعور بحركة الطفل لأول مرة ، و ..
You know you start getting a few of those flutters and kicks and..
و بدأت بالشعور بـعدد قليل من تلك الضربات والركلات و ..
i guess for the first few times you think is that the baby or is that gas
على ما أعتقد في المرات القليلة الأولى التي تعتقد فيها
But eventually realize it's the baby and then that's really exciting.
لكن في النهاية أدرك أنه الطفل و هذا مثير حقًا.
just physical changes like..
مجرد تغييرات جسدية مثل ..
my boobs just were getting bigger and starting to get a bit sore
كان ثديي يكبر وبدأت في الشعور بالألم قليلاً
and.
و.
I found that my nails and my hair was growing a lot more on a lot quicker.
لقد وجدت أن أظافري وشعري ينموان كثيرًا بشكل أسرع.
one thing for me my i could feel my hips
بالنسبة لي كنت اشعر أن وركي وأضلعي بدأت..
and my ribs starting to widen, so i started to stretch in the middle of the night.
في الاتساع ، لذلك بدأت في التمدد في منتصف الليل.
Off the wall cause of my ribs really hurt
بالإستناد علي الجدار بسبب الألم في ضلوعى
she did keep on vomiting.
استمرت في التقيؤ.
But now her body shape was actually changing
ولكن الآن كان شكل جسدها يتغير
which was perfect because i think ..
وهو ما كان مثالياً لأني أعتقد ..
you begin to
تبدأ في
form somewhat of an attachment to the fetus
تشكل نوعًا ما من الارتباط بالجنين
because you see that there is a belly there.
لأنك ترى أن هناك بطنًا.
the biggest physical changes for me
بدأت أكبر التغييرات الجسدية
were starting to show and just.
بالنسبة لي في الظهور
Clothes that i'm used to wearing they were getting a lot tighter.
الملابس التي اعتدت على ارتدائها أصبحت ضيقة أكثر.
it was a struggle to.
كان كفاحًا من أجل.
Feel.
لكي اشعر..
As good as i wanted to
جيدة كما أردت ان اكون.
I think the best thing you can do is to feel good about yourself
أعتقد أن أفضل شيء يمكنك فعله هو الشعور بالرضا عن
is to buy maternity clothes like buy clothes that..
نفسك هو شراء ملابس الأمومة مثل شراء الملابس التي ..
will lend to the changes in your body and you can put your favorite Jeans away
سوف تتكيف مع التغييرات في جسمك ويمكنك وضع
and just accept that.
الجينز المفضل لديك بعيدًا وقبول..
That's not the time for them now and then embrace the change.
ليس هذا هو الوقت المناسب لهم الآن وبعد ذلك تقبُل التغيير.
physical symptoms that you might need to go and seek help about.
الأعراض الجسدية التي قد تحتاج إلى الذهاب وطلب المساعدة بشأنها.
For example
على سبيل المثال ، إذا كنت تعاني من
you know if you have severe headaches, if you have spot in front of your eyes,
صداع شديد ، إذا كان لديك بقعة أمام عينيك ،
if you suddenly get a lot of swelling
إذا حدث تورم شديد فجأة
It's important to make sure that your blood pressure hasn't gone up.
من المهم التأكد من عدم ارتفاع ضغط الدم.
any bleeding.
أي نزيف.
Again you should you should seek help
مرة أخرى يجب عليك طلب المساعدة
but other than that
ولكن بخلاف ما تعلمين ، كل الآلام
you know, all the general aches and pains that you get during pregnancy
والأوجاع العامة التي تصيبك أثناء الحمل
are usually quite normal.
عادة ما تكون طبيعية تمامًا.
During the second trimester there's i guess what we call a settling into it.
خلال الثلث الثاني من الحمل ، أعتقد أن هناك ما نسميه الاستقرار و التعوّد.
You're starting to look pregnant
لقد بدأتِ تبدين حاملاً
you started to feel less sick sometimes you feel less tired
بدأت تشعرين بمرض أقل في بعض الأحيان
you've usually come to terms with it
تشعرين بتعب أقل ، وعادة ما تتصالح مع الأمر
it's a time when often you will have an ultrasound done.
إنه الوقت الذي غالبًا ما ستخضعين فيه لفحص الموجات فوق الصوتية.
that'll tell you that everything's okay with the baby.
سيخبرك هذا أن كل شيء على ما يرام مع الطفل.
So you tend to relax into it and start to really think about..
لذلك تميلين إلى الاسترخاء والبدء في التفكير حقًا في ..
Becoming a mum
أن تصبحي أماً
and society out there is starting to recognize you're pregnant and and they're reinforcing it.
والمجتمع بدأ يدرك أنك حامل وهم يعززون ذلك.
during that second trimester i felt i was able to control myself a lot more emotionally
خلال هذا الفصل الثاني شعرت أنني قادرة على التحكم في نفسي أكثر بكثير من الناحية العاطفية
i really made sure and it was really.
لقد تأكدت حقًا وكان ذلك حقًا.
Pushed on me by the midwives and also by..
دفعتني القابلات(مُمرضات التوليد) وأيضًا عائلتي
My family i really wanted to take care of myself if that was..
كنت أرغب حقًا في الاعتناء بنفسي إذا كان ذلك ..
Going to get a message, if that was..
سأحصل على تدليك ، إذا كان هذا ..
going shopping by myself for a little bit, if that was..
ذاهب للتسوق بنفسي قليلاً ، إذا كان ذلك ..
Just going to the movies going.
مجرد الذهاب لمشاهدة الأفلام
To dinner with my girlfriends it was.
او الذهاب لتناول العشاء مع صديقاتي.
During that time.
خلال ذلك الوقت.
I needed to make sure that i was happy
كنت بحاجة للتأكد من أنني كنت سعيدة
i think the only negative emotions i had was in relation to the body image.
أعتقد أن المشاعر السلبية الوحيدة التي شعرت بها كانت فيما يتعلق بشكل جسدي.
You know so that and the ongoing vomiting.
والقيء المستمر.
You know i think i felt pretty..
أعتقد أنني شعرت بـ ..
And because I've never have had a baby everyone would tell me
ولأنني لم أنجب طفلاً من قبل ، كان يخبرني الجميع..
it'll be worth it it'll be worth it, but..
سيكون الأمر يستحق ذلك ، ولكن ..
there was probably times where i thought is it really going to be worth it
ربما كانت هناك أوقات اعتقدت فيها هل سيكون حقًا يستحق ذلك
cause i feel so terrible, and i felt so terrible for so long.
لأنني أشعر بشعور رهيب للغاية ، وشعرت بالفزع الشديد لفترة طويلة.
There was some exhaustion as well.
كان هناك بعض الإرهاق أيضًا.
Because she was always throwing up so she couldn't
لأنها كانت تتقيأ دائمًا ، لذا لم تستطع فعل أي
she couldn't do anything else which meant that i had to step up looking after her.
شيء آخر ، مما يعني أنه كان عليّ أن أقوم برعايتها.
I think at some point i became, I was emotionally exhausted
أعتقد أنني في مرحلة ما أصبحت منهكاً عاطفيًا
which wasn't fair because
الذي لم يكن عادلاً لأنك تعلم ، لقد
you know, we did this together so why should she carry the burden of..
فعلنا هذا معًا فلماذا تتحمل عبء ..
having all the vomiting and the physical changes, and i'm just the observer
القيء والتغيرات الجسدية، وأنا مجرد مراقب
it's really important that men also find that support
من المهم حقًا أن يجد الرجال هذا الدعم أيضًا
so they may be in an environment where nobody has children.
لذلك قد يكونون في بيئة لا يوجد فيها أطفال.
None of the their..
لا أحد من ..
Siblings may have had children
قد يكون الأشقاء لديهم أطفال
so it's important also for dads to get that support and that network
لذلك من المهم أيضًا أن يحصل الآباء على هذا الدعم وتلك الشبكة
The support that i received was great
كان الدعم الذي تلقيته رائعًا
because you do a midwife clinic at the hospital, so..
لأني من اذهب لعيادة مُمرضات التوليد في المستشفى ، لذا ..
Depending again when you might have care you lay to see your private doctor..
اعتمادًا مرة أخرى على الوقت الذي قد يكون لديك فيه رعاية ، تستطيعين رؤية طبيبك الخاص ..
you could end up seeing them fortnightly or monthly but you can go there and share..
قد ينتهي بك الأمر برؤيتهم كل أسبوعين أو شهريًا ولكن يمكنك الذهاب إلى هناك ومشاركتهم ..
Any feelings anything that you going through the midwives will..
أي تقصير ، أي شعور تمر به ,القابلات سوف ..
generally ask you set questions.
بشكل عام بسألك أسئلة عامة.
If i felt like i ever needed help i would go seek help
إذا شعرت أنني بحاجة إلى المساعدة في أي وقت ..
and.
فسأذهب لطلب المساعدة.
It was always my first priority just to make sure..
كانت دائمًا أولويتي الأولى فقط للتأكد ..
My health and mental state of mind especially during my pregnancy was at its best
كانت حالتي الصحية والعقلية خاصة خلال فترة الحمل في أفضل حالاتها
yes, you know your pregnant in the first trimester and it's all very exciting..
نعم، أنت تعرفين أنك حامل في الأشهر الثلاثة الأولى وكل هذا مثير للغاية ..
but until you say that bump for you get that first kick it's not..
ولكن حتى ترين هذا النتوء او اول ركلة للجنين ..
for me it wasn't inherently real
بالنسبة لي لم يكن ذلك حقيقيًا
i think the reality of..
بطبيعته وأعتقد أن حقيقة ..
Adjusting to being a parent actually hit me in the second trimester to be honest.
لقد صدمني التكيف مع كوني اصبحت اباً في الثلث الثاني من الحمل لأكون صادقًا.
I mean..
أعني..
We've basically been in a relationship with each other
لقد كنا في الأساس على علاقة مع بعضنا البعض
looking after each other's needs.
الاعتناء باحتياجات بعضنا البعض.
Throughout the period that the time we were together
طوال الفترة التي كنا فيها معا
but now that she was -you know- about to have a baby.
لكنها الآن - كما تعلم - على وشك إنجاب طفل.
You know you start thinking about oh
أنت تعلم أنك تبدأ في التفكير في أوه
look we need
انظر نحن بحاجة
probably need more money
ربما نحتاج إلى المزيد من المال كما تعلم
you know she's probably going to be out of work for that period of time well.
أنها على الأرجح ستكون عاطلة عن العمل لتلك الفترة الزمنية.
He's still an infant baby.
بُني لا يزال رضيعًا.
So we started thinking about what we need to get and..
لذلك بدأنا بالتفكير في ما تحتاج إلى الحصول عليه و ..
and we did just after the second trimester start..
وفعلنا ذلك بعد بداية الفصل الثاني مباشرة ..
getting everything ready.
بتجهيز كل شيء.